{"tossups": [{"question": "This poem, which was written on a trip to visit the father of the author\u2019s lover Chester Kallman, was read on NPR following the 9/11 attacks. The \u201cDaisy\u201d Ad uses a variation of the final line from this poem, which states \u201cWe must love each other, or we must die.\u201d This poem\u2019s author claims he was \u201cin one of the dives / On Fifty-second Street\u201d when he heard the news of Germany invading Poland. For ten points, name this W.H. Auden poem written at, and named for, the start of World War II.", "answer": "<b> September 1, 1939</b>", "metadata": "Literature - American Literature - Poetry"}, {}, {}, {"question": "A key leader of this movement had a brother who helped win the Battle of Ayacucho and founded the newspaper<em> Northern Star</em>. This movement included striking miners in Cornwall in the Plug Plot Riots. Feargus O\u2019Connor led this movement, which indirectly increased suffrage via the 1867 Great Reform Bill. This movement called for secret ballots and annual elections for Parliament. For ten points, name this 19th century British working class movement for political reform that called for the vote for all men over age 21.", "answer": "<b> Chartism</b> (accept word forms, like<b> Chartist</b>s)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Bill Anthrell hosted an event at this university at which he claimed he was going to kill a dog with napalm. A lawsuit following the most famous event at this university targeted then-governor Jim Rhodes, who sent the National Guard to this university. Contrary to popular belief, a 14-year old runaway was not a student of this university, despite being depicted in a photograph next to one of the four students killed on May 4, 1970. For ten points, name this Ohio university where Vietnam War protesters were infamously shot.", "answer": "<b> Kent State</b> University", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "An infamous doctrine developed by this man prevented the extradition of terrorists back to Italy. This man signed the Gayssot Act to make denial of the Holocaust illegal. This man controversially ordered Operation Satan, the bombing of the Greenpeace ship<em> Rainbow Warrior</em> in New Zealand waters. This leader\u2019s tenure featured two<em> cohabitations</em> with Edouard Balladur and Jacques Chirac. For ten points, name this first socialist president of France.", "answer": "Francois<b> Mitterand</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "Description<em> not</em> acceptable; this has a name. The main inhabitant of this facility lived in the first of three security zones in an area protected from direct exposure to the sun. The Todt Organization built this facility near the town of Rastenberg in the Masurian woods. An assassination attempt at this location was known as Operation Valkyrie and failed on July 20, 1944, a few months before its occupant left it for an underground bunker in Berlin. For ten points, name this fortified residence that served as Hitler\u2019s headquarters on the Eastern Front.", "answer": "<b> Wolf\u2019s Lair</b> (or<b> Wolfsschanze</b>; do not accept or prompt on \u201cFuhrerbunker\u201d)", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "At its 1931 opening, this bridge surpassed the Ambassador Bridge as the longest bridge in the world. This bridge, which was originally slated to be named the Knickerbocker Bridge, terminates at Fort Lee on one side. For a week in September 2013, two of this bridge\u2019s three lanes were closed during rush hour traffic, a political punishment for Mark Sokolich for not supporting Chris Christie\u2019s run for Governor of New Jersey. For ten points, name this bridge across the Hudson River.", "answer": "<b> George Washington</b> Bridge (accept<b> GWB</b> or<b> GW</b> Bridge)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "This war, which was concentrated along the Daya River, was won by a king referred to in some texts as Priyadarsi. This war ended with a successful \u201cmission of the peace,\u201d according to the author of<em> Military</em> <em>History of Orissa</em>. The successor to Bindusara started this war, whose victor decided to devote himself to the principle of<em> ahimsa</em>, or non-violence. According to the thirteenth Rock Edict, over 150,000 members of the losing kingdom were killed by the Mauryans in, for ten points, what war that led Ashoka to convert to Buddhism?", "answer": "<b> Kalinga</b> War", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {"question": "The losing side\u2019s strategy during this battle was known as<em> Plan A-Go</em>. Despite the risk of submarine attacks, Marc Mitscher heroically turned on the lights of his flight decks to help fighter pilots return to safety during this battle. In a debriefing aboard the USS<em> Lexington</em> a pilot compared this battle to an\u201cold-time\u201d event \u201cdown home,\u201d hence providing the nickname \u201cGreat Marianas Turkey Shoot.\u201d The last carrier-on-carrier battle between the U.S. and Japan was, for ten points, what battle fought in a body of water bordering Mindanao?", "answer": "Battle of the<b> Philippine Sea</b> (accept<b> Great Marianas Turkey Shoot</b> before mentioned)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "While this man was meeting with Ho Chi Minh, Operation Cold Chop led to the capture of the Flagstaff House and this man\u2019s overthrow. Shortly after this man\u2019s Convention People\u2019s Party won a rigged election, he was deposed by Joseph Ankrah in a coup. This man, who gave the \u201cMotion of Destiny\u201dspeech in support of independence, joined Nasser as an African founder of the Non-Aligned Movement. The Akosombo Dam was built in the former Gold Coast under the leadership of, for ten points, what first president of Ghana?", "answer": "Kwame<b> Nkrumah</b>", "metadata": "History - World History"}, {}, {"question": "At the Battle of Cap Bon, this group killed over 10,000 Roman soldiers. These people\u2019s king Godigisel died while this group crossed the Rhine River with the Alans and the Suebi. This Germanic tribe fought Belisarius at the Battle of Ad Decimum and Tricamarum near their capital of Carthage. The Hasdingi and Silingi formed this group, which invaded Iberia before conquering North Africa. For ten points, name these Germanic people whose name sounds like a criminal that destroys property.", "answer": "<b> Vandal</b>s", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "Conspiracy theorists hold that this man froze the Knicks\u2019 envelope in the 1985 Draft Lottery, helping them win the first pick to draft Patrick Ewing.", "answer": "David<b> Stern</b>", "metadata": "Trash - Trash"}, {"question": "Linda Nash received over $5 million dollars for injuries received during this event, which resulted in six deaths. A tip given to Bill Miller of the Diplomatic Security Service resulted in the capture of this event\u2019s perpetrator, who said \u201cI am a terrorist and proud of it\u201d during his trial. Eyad Ismoil was involved in this event, which targeted the B-2 level of a parking garage in Manhattan. Ramzi Yousef carried out, for ten points, what 1993 terrorist attack in New York City?", "answer": "1993<b> W</b>orld<b> T</b>rade<b> C</b>enter<b> bombing</b> (accept descriptions of the 19<b>93 WTC attack</b>, or the <b>first WTC attack</b>; accept<b> Twin Towers</b> in place of WTC; prompt on partial answers, like \u201cterrorist attack against the World Trade Center\u201d, do not accept or prompt on<b> 9/11</b>)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}, {}, {"question": "This man\u2019s press secretary, Andr\u00b4e Singer, transformed this man\u2019s name into a term for a no-conflict, stable ideology. After leaving office at the end of 2010, this man\u2019s appointment as Chief of Staff under his successor was blocked by Gilmar Mendes [zheel-mar men-des]. A $1.1 million apartment was found to have been given to this man as a bribe as part of an investigation known as Operation Car Wash. This former leader of the Workers\u2019 Party was jailed after being convicted on money laundering charges in 2017. For ten points, name this predecessor of Dilma Rousseff as President of Brazil.", "answer": "Luiz Inacio<b> Lula</b> da<b> Silva</b> (accept either or both underlined parts)", "metadata": "Current Events - Current Events"}, {}, {"question": "<b>After this man failed to gain support for a bill legalizing denomination-based boarding schools, he was replaced in his post by Botho zu Eulenburg. The Agrarian League opposed this man for his support of free trade. Though he was able to secure Heligoland in an</b> <b>exchange for (+)</b> <b>Zanzibar, this man failed to renew his predecessor\u2019s Reinsurance Treaty</b> <b>with Russia. This man\u2019s \u201cNew Course\u201d policy aimed to improve relations with Great Britain, who ceded a (*)</b> Namibian strip named for this man to Germany. For ten points, name this successor of Otto von Bismarck as chancellor.", "answer": "Leo von<b> Caprivi</b>", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>This city\u2019s school system was the subject of the</b><em><b> Milliken v. Bradley</b></em><b> desegregation case in 1974. In the early 1980s, this city seized nearly 500 acres of private land in Poletown to</b> <b>build the Hamtramck factory, a move supported by mayor (+)</b> <b>Coleman Young. Governor</b> <b>Rick Snyder seized financial control over this city in March 2013; four months later, it (*) </b>declared bankruptcy, the largest US city to do so in history. White flight to suburbs like the Grosse Pointes and Troy has affected, for ten points, what largest city in Michigan?", "answer": "<b> Detroit</b>", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {"question": "<b>Limestone blocks cut into smaller</b><em><b> talatats</b></em><b> were used to construct this place, which some scholars believe was named a capital city because the shape of its \u201cGreat Wadi\u201d resembles a symbol meaning \u201chorizon.\u201d In this city, a bust of a woman whose husband was purged from historical records was sculpted by (+) Thutmose. A relief from this city is a \u201cwindow of appearance\u201d scene, where seated parents receive \u201clife-giving (*)</b> rays\u201d from ankhs extending from a solar disc. The pharaoh Akhenaten established, for ten points, what Egyptian city that became the center of his cult of worshiping Aten?", "answer": "<b> Amarna</b> (accept<b> Akhetaten</b>)", "metadata": "History - Ancient History"}, {}, {"question": "<b>This philosopher argued that, since a point is a place in space that takes up no space, it is best defined as \u201ca negation of itself.\u201d Karl Popper argued that the political philosophy of this one-time roommate of Schelling and Holderlin was a thinly veiled defense of (+) Frederick William III. A philosophical circle which included Max Stirner were the so called\u201cYoung\u201d followers of this thinker, in whose system a (*)</b> \u201cthesis\u201d and \u201cantithesis\u201d sublate into a\u201csynthesis.\u201d For ten points, name this philosopher who espoused his dialectical system in<em> The Science of</em> <em>Logic</em> and<em> The Phenomenology of Spirit</em>.", "answer": "Georg Wilhelm Friedrich<b> Hegel</b> [HAY-gull]", "metadata": "Philosophy - Philosophy"}, {"question": "<b>This composer requested no applause at the premiere of one of his works, which opens with a movement juxtaposing the</b><em><b> Kyrie</b></em> <b>[keer-ee-ay] with the tenor solo \u201cWhat passing bells</b> <b>for those who (+)</b> <b>die as cattle?\u201d Wilfred Owen poetry is used in that work, which this</b> <b>man helped conduct at its premiere at the re-consecration of (*)</b> Coventry Cathedral. Another work by this composer displays the various sections of an orchestra for children. For ten points, name this British composer of<em> War Requiem</em> and<em> The Young Person\u2019s Guide to the Orchestra</em>.", "answer": "Benjamin<b> Britten</b>", "metadata": "Fine Arts - Auditory Fine Arts"}, {"question": "<b>The name of the central group in this event was inspired by a French saying meaning\u201cComrade, let\u2019s get a drink.\u201d A man known as Ser Nuto was hung by one foot during this event. The Eight Saints were defeated during this event, whose leader was chosen after he walked barefoot into a palace. A group of (+) butchers carried out an attack in the Piazza della Signoria during this event. Michele [mik-ay-lay] di Lando became the (*)</b><em> Gonfaloniere</em> during this event, which was partly caused by anger at the quadrupling of guild entry fees. For ten points, name this 1378 revolt of Florentine woolworkers.", "answer": "<b> Ciompi</b> Revolt", "metadata": "History - European History"}, {"question": "<b>Description acceptable. During this campaign, George A. Dodd led the so-called \u201clast true cavalry charge.\u201d An officer in this campaign strapped two captured soldiers on the hood of his car and carved three notches in his pistols. Four \u201cflying columns\u201d were dispatched</b> <b>during this campaign, which saw fighting at the town of (+)</b> <b>Parral and the use of Buffalo</b> <b>Parral and the use of Buffalo</b> <b>Soldiers at Guerrero. \u00b4Alvaro Obreg\u00b4on threatened to attack this (*)</b> <b>Soldiers at Guerrero. \u00b4Alvaro Obreg\u00b4on threatened to attack this (*)</b> expedition, which began after the Division of the North attacked Columbus, New Mexico. For ten points, name this 1916-17 expedition led by John Pershing, a failed attempt to capture a Mexican soldier.", "answer": "<b> Punitive Expedition</b> (accept descriptions of John \u201cBlackjack\u201d Pershing\u2019s expedition to <b>capture</b> Pancho<b> Villa</b>; prompt on partial answers, including \u201cPershing\u2019s expedition\u201d)", "metadata": "History - American History"}, {}, {}], "bonuses": []}